Guide to the Office of Graduate Medical Education records, 1940-2001 RG0060
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
Office of Graduate Medical Education records
1940-2001
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
George Washington University. Office of Graduate Medical Education
RG0060
4.5 Linear Feet
This collection contains documents from the Graduate Medical Education Office at the George Washington University. The documents range from 1940-2001. Included are documents relating the Committee on Graduate Medical Education, Chief Residents and House Staff, Interns and residents, and other documents relating to the GME.
Acquisition Information
The collection is composed of transfers from the Graudate Medical Education. The original accession numbers are 321 and 1038.
Historical or Biographical Note
The Graduate Medical Education (GME) Office at The George Washington University Medical Center provides the leadership, structure and support necessary to achieve excellence in resident education.
The GME Office provides oversight for all Accreditation Council for Graduate Medical Education (ACGME) approved residencies at The George Washington University Medical Center and all of its affiliate institutions. The GME Office has most of the institutional administrative responsibility for the residency programs and maintains the permanent file for each resident. The primary objectives of this office are to assist residents in their relationship to the necessary administrative process and to assure that residents' responsibilities are met.
Arrangement
This collection is organized into four groupings: Committe on Graduate Medial Education, Chief Residents and House Staff, Intern and Resident committee, and General program documents. Within each groups the folders are arranged chronologically.
Scope and Contents
This collection contains information on: the Committe on Graduate Medial Education, Chief Residents and House Staff, Intern and Resident committee, and General program documents. The documents range from 1940-2001.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for research
Accreditation (Education); Committees; Budget
- Graduate Education Planning, 1973-1974; RG0060 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Graduate Education Planning, 1974-1975; RG0060 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Graduate Education Planning, 1975-1976; RG0060 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Graduate Education Planning, 1976-1977; RG0060 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Graduate Education Planning, 1977-1978; RG0060 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Graduate Education Planning, 1978-1979; RG0060 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Graduate Education Planning, 1979-1980; RG0060 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Graduate Medical Education, 1980-1981; RG0060 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Graduate Medical Education, 1981-1982; RG0060 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Graduate Medical Education, 1981-1982; RG0060 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Graduate Medical Education, 1981-1982; RG0060 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Graduate Medical Education, 1981-1982; RG0060 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Graduate Medical Education, 1982-1983; RG0060 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Graduate Medical Education, 1983-1984; RG0060 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Graduate Medical Education, 1984-1985; RG0060 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Graduate Medical Education, 1985-1986; RG0060 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Graduate Medical Education, 1986-1987; RG0060 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Graduate Medical Education, 1986-1987; RG0060 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Graduate Medical Education, 1986-1987; RG0060 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Graduate Medical Education, 1987-1988; RG0060 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Graduate Medical Education, 1988-1989; RG0060 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- GME Committee Minutes, September 1989; RG0060 (Box 8, Folder 126)
- GME Committee Minutes, October 1989; RG0060 (Box 8, Folder 125)
- GME Committee Minutes, November 1989; RG0060 (Box 8, Folder 124)
- GME Committee Minutes, December 1989; RG0060 (Box 8, Folder 123)
- GME Committee Minutes, February 1990; RG0060 (Box 8, Folder 122)
- GME Committee Minutes, March 1990; RG0060 (Box 8, Folder 121)
- GME Committee Minutes, April 1990; RG0060 (Box 8, Folder 120)
- GME Committee Minutes, May 1990; RG0060 (Box 8, Folder 119)
- GME Committee Minutes, June 1990; RG0060 (Box 8, Folder 118)
- GME Committee Minutes, August 1990; RG0060 (Box 8, Folder 117)
- GME Committee Minutes, September 1990; RG0060 (Box 8, Folder 116)
- GME Committee Minutes, October 1990; RG0060 (Box 8, Folder 115)
- GME Committee Minutes, November 1990; RG0060 (Box 8, Folder 114)
- GME Committee Minutes, December 1990; RG0060 (Box 8, Folder 113)
- GME Committee Minutes, January 1991; RG0060 (Box 8, Folder 112)
- GME Committee Minutes, March 1991; RG0060 (Box 8, Folder 111)
- GME Committee Minutes, April 1991; RG0060 (Box 8, Folder 110)
- GME Committee Minutes, May 1991; RG0060 (Box 8, Folder 109)
- GME Committee Minutes, June 1991; RG0060 (Box 8, Folder 108)
- GME Committee Minutes, July 1991; RG0060 (Box 8, Folder 107)
- GME Committee Minutes, September 1991; RG0060 (Box 8, Folder 106)
- GME Committee Minutes, November 1991; RG0060 (Box 8, Folder 105)
- GME Committee Minutes, December 1992; RG0060 (Box 8, Folder 96)
- GME Committee Minutes, January 1992; RG0060 (Box 8, Folder 104)
- GME Committee Minutes, February 1992; RG0060 (Box 8, Folder 103)
- GME Committee Minutes, March 1992; RG0060 (Box 8, Folder 102)
- GME Committee Minutes, May 1992; RG0060 (Box 8, Folder 101)
- GME Committee Minutes, June 1992; RG0060 (Box 8, Folder 100)
- GME Committee Minutes, August 1992; RG0060 (Box 8, Folder 99)
- GME Committee Minutes, September 1992; RG0060 (Box 8, Folder 98)
- GME Committee Minutes, October 1992; RG0060 (Box 8, Folder 97)
- GME Committee Minutes, February 1993; RG0060 (Box 8, Folder 95)
- GME Committee Minutes, March 1993; RG0060 (Box 8, Folder 94)
- GME Committee Minutes, April 1993; RG0060 (Box 8, Folder 93)
- GME Committee Minutes, June 1993; RG0060 (Box 8, Folder 92)
- GME Committee Minutes, July 1993; RG0060 (Box 8, Folder 91)
- GME Committee Minutes, August 1993; RG0060 (Box 8, Folder 90)
- GME Committee Minutes, September 1993; RG0060 (Box 8, Folder 89)
- GME Committee Minutes, October 1993; RG0060 (Box 8, Folder 88)
- GME Committee Minutes, December 1993; RG0060 (Box 8, Folder 87)
- GME Committee Minutes, January 1994; RG0060 (Box 8, Folder 86)
- GME Committee Minutes, February 1994; RG0060 (Box 8, Folder 85)
- GME Committee Minutes, June 1994; RG0060 (Box 8, Folder 84)
- GME Committee Minutes, July 1994; RG0060 (Box 8, Folder 83)
- GME Committee Minutes, August 1994; RG0060 (Box 8, Folder 82)
- GME Committee Minutes, September 1994; RG0060 (Box 8, Folder 81)
- GME Committee Minutes, October 1994; RG0060 (Box 8, Folder 80)
- GME Committee Minutes, November 1994; RG0060 (Box 8, Folder 79)
- GME Committee Minutes, December 1994; RG0060 (Box 8, Folder 78)
- GME Committee Minutes, January 1995; RG0060 (Box 8, Folder 77)
- GME Committee Minutes, February 1995; RG0060 (Box 8, Folder 76)
- GME Committee Minutes, March 1995; RG0060 (Box 8, Folder 75)
- GME Committee Minutes, April 1995; RG0060 (Box 8, Folder 74)
- GME Committee Minutes, May 1995; RG0060 (Box 8, Folder 73)
- GME Committee Minutes, June 1995; RG0060 (Box 8, Folder 72)
- GME Committee Minutes, July 1995; RG0060 (Box 8, Folder 71)
- GME Committee Minutes, August 1995; RG0060 (Box 8, Folder 70)
- GME Committee Minutes, September 1995; RG0060 (Box 8, Folder 69)
- GME Committee Minutes, October 1995; RG0060 (Box 8, Folder 68)
- GME Committee Minutes, December 1995; RG0060 (Box 8, Folder 66)
- GME Committee Minutes, November 1995; RG0060 (Box 8, Folder 67)
- GME Committee Minutes, January 1996; RG0060 (Box 8, Folder 65)
- GME Committee Minutes, February 1996; RG0060 (Box 8, Folder 64)
- GME Committee Minutes, March 1996; RG0060 (Box 8, Folder 63)
- GME Committee Minutes, April 1996; RG0060 (Box 8, Folder 62)
- GME Committee Minutes, May 1996; RG0060 (Box 8, Folder 61)
- GME Committee Minutes, July 1996; RG0060 (Box 8, Folder 60)
- GME Committee Minutes, August 1996; RG0060 (Box 8, Folder 59)
- GME Committee Minutes, September 1996; RG0060 (Box 8, Folder 58)
- GME Committee Minutes, October 1996; RG0060 (Box 8, Folder 57)
- GME Committee Minutes, November 1996; RG0060 (Box 8, Folder 56)
- GME Committee Minutes, December 1996; RG0060 (Box 8, Folder 55)
- GME Committee Minutes, December 1997; RG0060 (Box 8, Folder 43)
- GME Committee Minutes, January 1997; RG0060 (Box 8, Folder 54)
- GME Committee Minutes, February 1997; RG0060 (Box 8, Folder 53)
- GME Committee Minutes, March 1997; RG0060 (Box 8, Folder 52)
- GME Committee Minutes, April 1997; RG0060 (Box 8, Folder 51)
- GME Committee Minutes, May 1997; RG0060 (Box 8, Folder 50)
- GME Committee Minutes, June 1997; RG0060 (Box 8, Folder 49)
- GME Committee Minutes, July 1997; RG0060 (Box 8, Folder 48)
- GME Committee Minutes, August 1997; RG0060 (Box 8, Folder 47)
- GME Committee Minutes, September 1997; RG0060 (Box 8, Folder 46)
- GME Committee Minutes, October 1997; RG0060 (Box 8, Folder 45)
- GME Committee Minutes, November 1997; RG0060 (Box 8, Folder 44)
- GME Committee Minutes, January 1998; RG0060 (Box 8, Folder 42)
- GME Committee Minutes, February 1998; RG0060 (Box 8, Folder 41)
- GME Committee Minutes, March 1998; RG0060 (Box 8, Folder 40)
- GME Committee Minutes, April 1998; RG0060 (Box 8, Folder 39)
- GME Committee Minutes, May 1998; RG0060 (Box 8, Folder 38)
- GME Committee Minutes, June 1998; RG0060 (Box 8, Folder 37)
- Graduate Medical Education Committee meeting minutes, July 1998; RG0060 (Box 8, Folder 36)
- Graduate Medical Education Committee meeting minutes, August 1998; RG0060 (Box 8, Folder 35)
- Graduate Medical Education Committee meeting minutes, September 1998; RG0060 (Box 8, Folder 34)
- Graduate Medical Education Committee meeting minutes, October 1998; RG0060 (Box 8, Folder 33)
- Graduate Medical Education Committee meeting minutes, November 1998; RG0060 (Box 8, Folder 32)
- Graduate Medical Education Committee meeting minutes, December 1998; RG0060 (Box 8, Folder 31)
- Graduate Medical Education Committee meeting minutes, January 1999; RG0060 (Box 8, Folder 30)
- Graduate Medical Education Committee meeting minutes, February 1999; RG0060 (Box 8, Folder 29)
- Graduate Medical Education Committee meeting minutes, March 1999; RG0060 (Box 8, Folder 28)
- Graduate Medical Education Committee meeting minutes, April 1999; RG0060 (Box 8, Folder 27)
- Graduate Medical Education Committee meeting minutes, May 1999; RG0060 (Box 8, Folder 26)
- Graduate Medical Education Committee meeting minutes, June 1999; RG0060 (Box 8, Folder 25)
- Graduate Medical Education Committee meeting minutes, July 1999; RG0060 (Box 8, Folder 24)
- Graduate Medical Education Committee meeting minutes, August 1999; RG0060 (Box 8, Folder 23)
- Graduate Medical Education Committee meeting minutes, September 1999; RG0060 (Box 8, Folder 22)
- Graduate Medical Education Committee meeting minutes, October 1999; RG0060 (Box 8, Folder 21)
- Graduate Medical Education Committee meeting minutes, November 1999; RG0060 (Box 8, Folder 20)
- Graduate Medical Education Committee meeting minutes, December 1999; RG0060 (Box 8, Folder 19)
- Graduate Medical Education Committee meeting minutes, January 2000; RG0060 (Box 8, Folder 18)
- Graduate Medical Education Committee meeting minutes, February 2000; RG0060 (Box 8, Folder 17)
- Graduate Medical Education Committee meeting minutes, March 2000; RG0060 (Box 8, Folder 16)
- Graduate Medical Education Committee meeting minutes, April 2000; RG0060 (Box 8, Folder 15)
- Graduate Medical Education Committee meeting minutes, May 2000; RG0060 (Box 8, Folder 14)
- Graduate Medical Education Committee meeting minutes, June 2000; RG0060 (Box 8, Folder 13)
- Graduate Medical Education Committee meeting minutes, July 2000; RG0060 (Box 8, Folder 12)
- Graduate Medical Education Committee meeting minutes, August 2000; RG0060 (Box 8, Folder 11)
- Graduate Medical Education Committee meeting minutes, September 2000; RG0060 (Box 8, Folder 10)
- Graduate Medical Education Committee meeting minutes, October 2000; RG0060 (Box 8, Folder 9)
- Graduate Medical Education Committee meeting minutes, November 2000; RG0060 (Box 8, Folder 8)
- Graduate Medical Education Committee meeting minutes, December 2000; RG0060 (Box 8, Folder 7)
- Graduate Medical Education Committee meeting minutes, January 2001; RG0060 (Box 8, Folder 6)
- Graduate Medical Education Committee meeting minutes, February 2001; RG0060 (Box 8, Folder 5)
- Graduate Medical Education Committee meeting minutes, March 2001; RG0060 (Box 8, Folder 4)
- Graduate Medical Education Committee meeting minutes, April 2001; RG0060 (Box 8, Folder 3)
- Graduate Medical Education Committee meeting minutes, May 2001; RG0060 (Box 8, Folder 2)
- Graduate Medical Education Committee meeting minutes, June 2001; RG0060 (Box 8, Folder 1)
- Chief Residents Meeting, 1968-1971; RG0060 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Chief Residents Committee [1/2], 1990-1992; RG0060 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Chief Residents Committee [2/2], 1990-1992; RG0060 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- House Staff Training Program, 1963-1973; RG0060 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- House Staff Training Program, 1964-1974; RG0060 (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Precedent Book for House Starff, 1953-1955; RG0060 (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Precedent Book for House Officers, 1955-1957; RG0060 (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Precedent Book for House Officers, 1957-1959; RG0060 (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Precedent Book for House Officers, 1959-1961; RG0060 (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Precedent Book for House Officers, 1961-1962; RG0060 (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Intern and Resident committee, 1940-1949; RG0060 (Box 6, Folder 1)
- Intern and Resident committee, 1950-1959; RG0060 (Box 6, Folder 2)
- Intern and Resident Fellowships and awards, 1951-1971; RG0060 (Box 6, Folder 3)
- Intern and Resident committee, 1960-1963; RG0060 (Box 6, Folder 4)
- Intern and Resident committee, 1964-1965; RG0060 (Box 6, Folder 5)
- Intern and Resident committee, 1966; RG0060 (Box 6, Folder 6)
- Intern and Resident committee, 1967; RG0060 (Box 6, Folder 7)
- Intern and Resident committee, 1968-1969; RG0060 (Box 6, Folder 8)
- GME Miscellaneous, 1956-1973; RG0060 (Box 7, Folder 1)
- Program accreditation, 1962-1974; RG0060 (Box 7, Folder 2)
- Medical Director committee, 1969-1974; RG0060 (Box 7, Folder 3)
- Medical Center Graduate Medical Education Programs, 1980-1988; RG0060 (Box 7, Folder 4)
- Application to Residency Review Committee for Obstetrics/Gynecology, 1987; RG0060 (Box 7, Folder 5)
- Internship, Residency and Fellowships, Undated; RG0060 (Box 7, Folder 6)